



rajan rawat

♥ Noida, Uttar Pradesh. India.

□ +91 8130735880

☑ mail.rajanrawat@gmail.com
③ rajanrawat.github.io

I am passionate about building great products that deliver value for customers utilizing my Software Engineering background with over 13 years of experience in various business domains, including banking, payments, insurance and more.

Currently working as a Technical Product / Project Manager, I possess good analytical, technical and client relationship management skills with the ability to relate to people at multiple levels of business and management.

Clients

Slide Alfa I have worked on various projects from start-ups to large scale enterprises that required me to work closely with clients and end users.

Seguros Bolivar MIMO Technologies Pvt. Ltd. PictureTime Digiplex Pvt. Ltd. While leading technical projects, I have guided the back end and front-end sides of high-impact projects and established best practice standards. I have acted as the primary interface between developers and other teams within my organization. This has given me an opportunity to collaborate and work with other disciplines such as marketing, sales, business development and operations to deliver solutions that meet customer needs.

Skills & Tools

Technology Stack

Work History

Agile | Scrum | Project Management
Project Initiation | Estimation | Planning | Execution |
Change and Risk Management

Jira | Figma | Trello | Asana | Slack | Notion Office365 | GSuite

Adobe Photoshop | Premier Pro | After Effects

Microservices | REST API | SOAP Web Services

Oracle | MySQL | MongoDB | Postgres | Firebase

VS Code | Eclipse | GitHub | Bitbucket | GitLab | SVN

HTML | CSS | JavaScript | ¡Query | Bootstrap

Java | Spring | Struts | JPA | Hibernate

Apache | Tomcat | WebLogic | Nginx

Project Manager - TraQiQ Solutions Pvt. Ltd. (Apr 2016 - Present)

Spearheading Development Teams for Slide, Alfa, Seguros Bolivar, PictureTime and MIMO Technologies. Key responsibilities:

☑ Consulting and Strategize Technology roadmaps for Slide, Alfa, Seguros Bolivar, PictureTime and MIMO Technologies.

☑ Project Planning and Scope Definitions.

✓ Resource Planning and Time Estimations.

☑ Delivery Schedules.

☑ Change and Risk Management.

☑ Detailed Sprint plans with new features and product backlogs.

☑ Design overall architecture of the web applications.

 $f ext{$arphi}$ Collaborate with the client team to design and launch new features.

☑ Detailed Sprint plans with new features and product backlogs.

Maintain code integrity and organization.

 $\ensuremath{\ensuremath{\mbox{\noto}}}$ Understanding and implementation of security and data protection.

Technology Lead - Mann India Technologies Pvt. Ltd. (Jul 2014 - Mar 2016)

Mentoring a team of 15-20 Developers in SIMON application for Seguros Bolivar.

Key responsibilities:

Roles

Product Manager

Project Manager

Technology Lead
Onsite Client Coordinator

Developer

Technical Consultant

☑ Reengineering Legacy System in Seguros Bolivar Colombia.

✓ Interface with business users to gather business requirements.

Analysis of client needs, identify and suggest the best technical solutions.

☑ Design and execute proofs-of-concept, Prototypes for critical enterprise capabilities.

☑ Create design specification and framework for the application.

✓ Leading the development of the application.

☑ Create user stories, estimations and task breakup.

☑ Maintain quality and responsiveness of applications.

✓ Active involvement in Sprint plan meetings.

Resource handling.

Sr. Software Engineer - Mann India Technologies Pvt. Ltd. (Jun 2010 - Jun 2014)
Software Engineer - Mann India Technologies Pvt. Ltd. (Nov 2008 - May 2010)

Languages

Academic Qualification

English ★ ★ ★ ☆ ☆
Hindi ★ ★ ★ ★ ☆

Uttar Pradesh Technical University (2004-2008) - Computer Science Engineering Bachelors in Technology

CBSE - Kendriya Vidyalaya FRI, Dehradun (2004)

Spanish ★ ☆ ☆ ☆ CISCE - Carman School, Dehradun (2002)